Bauchwitz, Kurt (Roy C. Bates); Papers ger011
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
- Correspondence Files, 1914-1987; 2; 1 Digital Files 429 file folders
  - Correspondence with Family and Friends, 1914-1987; 2.1; 89 file folders
    - Breusing, Ima, 1914, 1918; 1947-1968 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 3)
      26 letters and cards from; 26 letters to.
    - Breusing, Ima, Undated (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 4)
      Death notice; memorial address by Pastor Dr. Heinold Fast. Mimeo. 9p.; exhibit brochure.
    - Breusing-Keller, Hildegard (Kell), 1950-1974 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 5)
      30 letters from; 17 letters to.
    - Bry, (Dr.) Ilse - Correspondence, 1957-1972; 2.1.16 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 6-9)
      111 letters from; 132 letters to.
      - Correspondence, 1957-1961 (Box 2 (2.1.16-Bry, (Dr.) Ilse - Correspondence), Folder 6)
      - Correspondence, 1962-1964 (Box 2 (2.1.16-Bry, (Dr.) Ilse - Correspondence), Folder 7)
      - Correspondence, 1965-1972 (Box 2 (2.1.16-Bry, (Dr.) Ilse - Correspondence), Folder 8)
      - Reprints, typescripts of articles, 22 items (Box 2 (2.1.16-Bry, (Dr.) Ilse - Correspondence), Folder 9)
    - Cappers, Rosemary (Posy), 1985-1990 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 10)
      25 letters from, 1 letter to.
    - Caramagno, Salvatore & Carol, 1960-1970 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 11)
      16 letters from, 16 letters to.
    - Carla (?), 1947 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 12)
      2 letters from.
    - Catarivas, Irene and David, 1965-1972 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 13)
      6 letters from, 6 letters to.
    - Chasen, Ilse (Icy), 1957-1971 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 14)
      71 postcards, letters from; 20 letters to; 1 photograph.
    - Chmiel, Elizabeth & Frank, 1956-1967 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 15)
      17 letters from, 3 letters to; 3 newspaper cl.
    - Close, Kathryn, 1957-1966 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 16)
      4 letters from, 5 letters to.
    - Derrick, Felix O. & Margareth, 1943-1957 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 17)
      2 letters from, 1 letter to.
    - Echandia, Rose and Paul, 1947-1969 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 18)
      6 letters, cards from; 2 letters to; 1 photograph.
    - Ehrenfels, Baron Umar Rolf & Mireille Abeille von. Correspondence with Roy C. Bates, 1939-1974; 2.1.26 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 19-33)
      152 letters from, 174 letters to; correspondence with Barbara Bates, 1973-1987: 84 L. from, 103 letters to; photographs; manuscripts and typescripts; clippings and reprints by and about.
      - Correspondence, 1939-1953 (Box 2 (2.1.26-Ehrenfels, Baron Umar Rolf & Mireille Abeille von.), Folder 19)
      - Correspondence, 1954-1961 (Box 2 (2.1.26-Ehrenfels, Baron Umar Rolf & Mireille Abeille von.), Folder 20)
      - Correspondence, 1962-1968 (Box 2 (2.1.26-Ehrenfels, Baron Umar Rolf & Mireille Abeille von.), Folder 21)
      - Correspondence, 1969-1974 (Box 2 (2.1.26-Ehrenfels, Baron Umar Rolf & Mireille Abeille von.), Folder 22)
      - Correspondence, 1974-1977 (Box 2 (2.1.26-Ehrenfels, Baron Umar Rolf & Mireille Abeille von.), Folder 23)
      - Correspondence, 1978-1987 (Box 2 (2.1.26-Ehrenfels, Baron Umar Rolf & Mireille Abeille von.), Folder 24)
      - Photographs (Box 2 (2.1.26-Ehrenfels, Baron Umar Rolf & Mireille Abeille von.), Folder 25)
        14 photographs of Rolf [U.R.], Mireille, and children, Mou'min and Leela.
      - Ehrenfels, U.R. von. "Brief Memorandum on my Flight & Internment 1938 till 1968" (Box 2 (2.1.26-Ehrenfels, Baron Umar Rolf & Mireille Abeille von.), Folder 26)
        Typescript cc. with h. corr. 4p.
      - Ehrenfels, U.R. von. "'Der Lebendige' - eine Wiederentdeckung" (Box 2 (2.1.26-Ehrenfels, Baron Umar Rolf & Mireille Abeille von.), Folder 27)
        Typescript cc. wiht h. corr. 9p.
      - Abeille, Mireille and U.R. von Ehrenfels. "Une inconnue: le poids d'un nom" (Box 2 (2.1.26-Ehrenfels, Baron Umar Rolf & Mireille Abeille von.), Folder 28)
        Typescript with h. corr. 23p. Notes. Autograph 3p.
      - Ehrenfels, U.R. von, 1948-1959; 24 items (Box 2 (2.1.26-Ehrenfels, Baron Umar Rolf & Mireille Abeille von.), Folder 29)
        Reprints and cl. by.
      - Ehrenfels, U.R. von, 1960-1970; 32 items (Box 2 (2.1.26-Ehrenfels, Baron Umar Rolf & Mireille Abeille von.), Folder 30)
      - Ehrenfels, U.R. von, 17 items (Box 2 (2.1.26-Ehrenfels, Baron Umar Rolf & Mireille Abeille von.), Folder 31)
        Reprints and cl. about.
      - Abeille von Ehrenfels, Mireille. Offprints and cl. by, 1965-1971; 11 items (Box 2 (2.1.26-Ehrenfels, Baron Umar Rolf & Mireille Abeille von.), Folder 32)
      - Ellenwood, Cynthia (New Generation Campus Ministries), 1973; 1989 (Box 2 (2.1.26-Ehrenfels, Baron Umar Rolf & Mireille Abeille von.), Folder 33)
        2 letters from, 2 newsletters.
    - Friede, Eva & Hans. Correspondence, 1941-1974; 2.1.27 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 1-3)
      140 letters and cards from; 81 letters to.
      - Correspondence, 1941-1960 (Box 3 (2.1.27-Friede, Eva & Hans. Correspondence), Folder 1)
      - Correspondence, 1961-1968 (Box 3 (2.1.27-Friede, Eva & Hans. Correspondence), Folder 2)
      - Correspondence, 1969-1974 (Box 3 (2.1.27-Friede, Eva & Hans. Correspondence), Folder 3)
    - Hiratsuka, Shig & Aiko, 1952-1974 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 4)
      4 letters from; 4 letters to.
    - Kopp, Ernst and Maria, 1947-1949 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 5)
      6 letters from.
    - Kühn-Leitz, (Dr.) Elsie, 1952-1970 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 6)
      21 letters, cards from; 24 letters to.
    - Texts of lectures by Elsie ühn-Leitz, Undated; 5 items (Box 3 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 7)
    - Kuhn-Leitz, Elsie: Photographs, including several of Albert Schweitzer, Undated; 7 items (Box 3 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 8)
    - Leiber, Willy, 1958 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 9)
      2 letters from, 2 letters to.
    - Makower, Hedwig & Gerhard, 1946 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 10)
      10 letters from.
    - Mann, Erika, 1940-1962 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 11)
      18 letters from, 28 letters to, 14 related letters.
    - Mann, Erika. Newspaper cl, Undated; 9 items (Box 3 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 12)
    - Mann, Golo, 1974 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 13)
    - Mann, Katharina (Katja), 1958 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 14)
    - Mann, Klaus, 1946 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 15)
    - Pavell, Eric, 1939; 1947 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 16)
      1 letter from, 1 letter to.
    - Reichenbach, Ilse & Bernhard. Correspondence, 1947-1984; 2.1.41 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 17-19)
      116 letters and cards from, 88 letters to; 3 clippings.
      - Correspondence, 1947-1965 (Box 3 (2.1.41-Reichenbach, Ilse & Bernhard. ), Folder 17)
      - Correspondence, 1966-1974 (Box 3 (2.1.41-Reichenbach, Ilse & Bernhard. ), Folder 18)
      - Correspondence with Barbara Bates, 1974-1984 (Box 3 (2.1.41-Reichenbach, Ilse & Bernhard. ), Folder 19)
    - Reig, Manuel (son of Ursula Schwarz), 1948-1952 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 20)
      2 letters from, 2 letters to; manuscripts of musical compositions. 4 items; 1 photograph.
    - Roth, Walter, 1939-1948 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 21)
      8 letters from, 1 related letter.
    - Schmidt, Madeleine Abecassius, 1939-1974 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 22)
      6 letters from; 3 photographs.
    - Schottmüller, Dora, 1946 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 23)
      1 letter from, 1 related letter.
    - Schwab, Anneliese & Edgar, 1941-1974 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 24)
      11 letters, cards from; 4 letters to.
    - Schwabach, Ella, 1963-1964 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 25)
      1 letter from, 1 letter to; death notice.
    - Schwarz, Ursula, 1946-1951 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 26)
      17 letters from.
    - Seelig, Martha, 1945 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 27)
    - Serbac, Jean-Rudolphe, 1955-1973 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 28)
      3 letters from, 1 letter to; 2 announcements.
    - Sernau, Gunther, 1951 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 29)
    - Sernau, Paul, 1941; 1946 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 30)
    - Serneaux-Gregorin (Sernau), Charlotte (née Bauchwitz, sister), 1939-1975 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 31)
      19 letters from, 3 letters to; 2 newspaper cl.; 12 slides of paintings by Serneaux-Gregori.
    - Shinada, (Prof.) Toyoharu, 1939-1971 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 32)
      26 letters, cards from, 16 letters to; 3 photographs.
    - Steubel, Hanna (daughter of Ima Breusing), 1967-1972 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 33)
      12 letters from, 8 letters to.
    - Strauss, Hilde & H[ans] Alexander, 1941-1949; 1970-1973 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 34)
      26 letters from, 2 letters to.
    - Walter, Trude, 1941-1974 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 35)
      6 letters from, 1 letter to.
    - Wedekind, Gerhard & Ruth, 1960-1971 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 36)
      22 letters, cards from, 22 letters to.
    - Winkelmann, Herbert, 1951 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 37)
  - Legal Correspondence, 1940-1974; 2.2; 1 Digital Files 71 file folders
    This series includes correspondence (595 letters) with colleagues, as well as correspondence relating to Bates' admission to law schools, admission to the New York State bar in 1957, admission to the Massachusetts State Bar in 1963, in addition to correspondence concerning various legal matters. Most notable among the correspondents are: Hermann J. Abs, Walter J. Derenberg, Martin Domke, Fritz Heßler, Joseph Kaskell. This sub-series also contains Bates' correspondence with the Berlin Entschädigungsamt (reparations bureau), 1955-1973.
    - Abs, Hermann J. / International Cooperation Administration, 1957-1958 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 38)
      5 letters from, 12 letters to; also text by Roy C. Bates entitled "Concerning 'Magna Carta'". Dated November 1957. Typescript cc. 2 c., 15p. ea. Original draft. Typescript and cc. 24p.
    - Abs, Hermann J. Newspaper cl.; notes by Bates; text by Abs, "Internationale Probleme und Fragen der Investitionsfinanzierung", Undated (Box 3 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 39)
      Pc. 23p.
    - American Bar Association, Chicago, 1961-1969 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 40)
      Correspondence, membership information, membership cards, miscellaneous publications.
    - American Branch of the International Law Association (New York). Correspondence, including newsletters, 1959-1969; 38 items (Box 3 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 41)
    - American Branch of the International Law Association, 1958-1966 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 42)
      Conference materials; notes; cl.
    - Arnold, Fritz W., 1961 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 43)
      6 letters from, 5 letters to.
    - The Association of the Bar of the City of New York. Correspondence, materials concerning membership, 1959-1967; ca. 40 items (Box 3 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 44)
      miscellaneous notes; cl.
    - Bratlie, Oisten J., 1962 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 45)
      2 letters to.
    - Breslauer, Ernest, 1949 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 46)
    - Carlsmith & Carlsmith (Carl S. Carlsmith), 1940-1942 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 47)
      11 letters from, 4 letters to.
    - Committee for the Study of Mankind (Gerhard Hirschfeld, Executive Director), 1960-1962 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 48)
      4 letters from, 5 letters to; cl.; notes.
    - Publications issued by the Committee for the Study of Mankind, 1958-1962; 9 items (Box 3 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 49)
    - Continuing Education of the Bar, 1963 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 50)
    - Crawford, William H., 1955-1962 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 51)
      7 letters from, 6 letters to.
    - Derenberg, Walter J., 1955-1962 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 52)
      5 letters from, 10 letters to; 2 articles about Derenberg.
    - Domke, Martin (American Arbitration Association), 1956-1960 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 53)
      6 letters from, 6 letters to; brochures. 6 items.
    - Draper, Ambassador William H., 1952 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 54)
      1 letter to; 2 newspaper cl.
    - Entschädigungsamt Berlin (Hans Strauss, Berliner Handels-Gesellschaft), 1955-1973 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 55)
      correspondence, records of bank transfers, legal documents. ca. 175p.
    - Entschädigungsamt Berlin, 1974-1995 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 56)
      Correspondence with Barbara Bates. ca. 70p.
    - Galleski, Werner, 1961-1962 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 57)
      1 letter from, 3 letters to.
    - Hartwig, Prof. (Halle-Wittenberg), 1956 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 58)
    - Heßler, Fritz, 1950-1971 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 59)
      30 letters from, 19 letters to.
    - Howald, Max, 1942 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 60)
    - Hoy, Robert L., 1995 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 61)
    - Institut d'Etudes Juridiques Européennes (Institute of European Judicial Studies), 1962 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 1)
      1 letter from, 2 letters to; pamphlet.
    - Kahn, Oscar, 1967 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 2)
    - Karelsen, Eph A., 1941; 1957 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 3)
      3 letters from, 2 letters to.
    - Karlen, Delmar, 1959-1960 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 4)
    - Kaskell, Joseph, 1957-1974 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 5)
      13 letters from, 18 letters to.
    - Kaskell, Peter, 1960 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 6)
    - Kessler, Friedrich, 1961 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 7)
      3 letters to.
    - Landesausgleichsamt Berlin, 1964 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 8)
    - Law directories. Correspondence, 1957-1963 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 9)
      re: Bates' listing in various law directories. ca. 15 items.
    - Law schools - Correspondence re: admissions, grades; miscellaneous catalogs, Undated; 2.2.34 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 10-13)
      - St. John's University, 1952-1954 (Box 4 (2.2.34-Law schools - Correspondence re: admissions, grade), Folder 10)
        Correspondence re: admissions. 13 items.
      - St. John's University. Records of tuition payments, grade reports, catalogs (Box 4 (2.2.34-Law schools - Correspondence re: admissions, grade), Folder 11)
      - New York University, 1954-1956 (Box 4 (2.2.34-Law schools - Correspondence re: admissions, grade), Folder 12)
        Correspondence, grade reports. 12 items.
      - New York University. Records of tuition payments, course listings (Box 4 (2.2.34-Law schools - Correspondence re: admissions, grade), Folder 13)
    - Lawyer's Placement Bureau (William R. Howells, Placement Director), 1962 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 14)
    - The Legal Translating Service (Stephen A. Goddard), Undated (Box 4 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 15)
      1 letter from, 1 letter to; 1 cl.
    - Loeser, Hans F., 1961 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 16)
    - Major, Stephen C., 1949 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 17)
    - Massachusetts, The Commonwealth of, Board of Bar Examiners. Correspondence, 1961-1962 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 18)
      re: admission to the Massachusetts Bar. 7 items; notes.
    - McNiece, Harold F., 1959 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 19)
    - Meagher, Thomas, 1961 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 20)
      2 letters from, 4 letters to.
    - Morse, Joseph L., 1957 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 21)
      1 letter from, 2 letters to.
    - Moses, Fritz, 1962 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 22)
    - Naidu, (Mrs.) P. Parijatham (Planning Commission, New Delhi, India), 1952-1957 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 23)
      3 letters, cards from, 2 letters to.
    - New York State Bar Association, 1957 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 24)
    - New York State Court of Appeals, 1963 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 25)
    - Nishi, Michio, 1967 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 26)
      3 letters, cards from, 1 letter to.
    - Nohara, Njuta, 1946-1954 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 27)
      3 letters from, 1 letter to; notes.
    - NYU Club, 1956-1960; 7 items (Box 4 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 28)
      Club Newsletter, 1958-1960.
    - Peters, Walter, 1963 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 29)
    - Raas, Emil, 1949 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 30)
    - Re, Professor, 1953 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 31)
      6 letters to; notes.
    - Rheinstein, Max, 1959-1960 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 32)
    - Rieser, S., 1942-1946 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 33)
      24 letters from, 4 letters to.
    - Rodach Books, Inc., 1965 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 34)
    - Rothe, Ernest E., 1957 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 35)
      1 letter to; death notice.
    - Schlesinger, Rudolf, Undated (Box 4 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 36)
    - Schlumbohm, Peter, 1941; 1961 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 37)
      3 letters from, 1 letter to.
    - Schwamberger, Wolfgang, 1963-1964 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 38)
      2 letters from, 3 letters to.
    - Skrzeba, Heinz, 1964 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 39)
    - Spellman, Howard Hilton, 1959 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 40)
    - State Board of Law Examiners, Albany, NY. Correspondence, 1956 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 41)
      re. taking the New York State Bar exam. 10 items.
    - Travel law. Correspondence between R.C.B. and various transportation companies, including sample tickets from companies, 1959 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 42)
      22 letters; notes; cl.
    - U. S. District Court for the District of Massachusetts. Correspondence, 1962; 11 items (Box 4 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 43)
    - Washington World Conference on World Peace Through Law, 1965 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 44)
      8 letters; notes.
    - Wergin, Kurt (Berlin), 1957 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 45)
    - Whiteside II, Alexander, 1975-1994 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 46)
      Including correspondence concerning publication arrangements with Harry Zohn, Last Will and Testament of Barbara Bates: 12 letters from, 12 letters to, 5 related letters.
    - Williams, C. Dickerman, 1960 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 47)
  - Correspondence regarding Literary Topics, 1941-1976; 2.3; 125 file folders
    This sub-series contains the correspondence (1031 letters) of Roy C. (and Barbara) Bates pertaining to his publication efforts, and includes correspondence with publishers of newspapers and literary journals concerning Bates' articles and poems submitted for publication, as well as correspondence with other writers, editors, etc. Notable among the correspondents in this section are: Eric Amann (Haiku Magazine), Max Brod, Albert Camus (1 L.), editors of Deutsche Blätter (Udo Rukser, Albert Theile), Douglas Harding, Fritz Martini, Carson McCullers, Heinz and Therese Mode, editors of the Saturday Review of Literature (Norman Cousins, Harrison Smith, John G. Fuller), Arthur Shapiro, Manes Sperber, Wayne Wonderly and Harry Zohn.
    - The Alabama Journal / Montgomery Advertiser, 1966 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 48)
    - Allen, Frederick L. (Editor, Harper's Magazine), 1966 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 49)
    - Amann, Eric (Haiku Magazine). Correspondence, 1968-1969 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 50)
      "New Year's Day". 12 "contest" Haiku. Typescript cc. 3p.
      "Syllables". Haiku. Typescript cc. 3p.
      "Question Mark". Typescript 3p.
      "What Does a Haiku Mean?" Typescript cc. 2p.
      "Authentic Interpretation of Haiku". Typescript cc. 2p.
      8 letters from, 13 letters to; manuscript submissions by Roy C. Bates:.
    - American Bar Association Journal, 1961-1971 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 51)
      10 letters from, 17 letters to. Includes carbons of letters from Bates later published in the Journal.
    - American Society for Psychical Research Journal (L. A. Dale, Editor), 1971 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 52)
    - Anshen, Ruth Nanda (Editor, World Perspectives), 1959 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 53)
    - Artin, E. (G. & C. Merriam Company), 1950 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 54)
    - The Atlantic Monthly, 1949-1967 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 55)
      3 letters from, 2 letters to; miscellaneous notes, materials. 5 items.
    - Auden, W[ystan] H[ughes], 1970 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 56)
      1 letter to; miscellaneous notes, materials. 4 items.
    - Beitzke, (Prof.) Günther, 1958 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 57)
    - Benzaquin, Paul (WEEI), 1967 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 58)
      1 letter from, 2 letters to; 1 cl.
    - Berkau, Günther (Aurum Verlag), 1977-1978 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 59)
      1 letter from, 5 letters to.
    - Berliner Schriftstellerverband (Hertha v. Gebhardt), 1949-1950 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 60)
      5 letters from, 4 letters to; 2 cl.
    - Bloch, Ernst, 1967 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 61)
      1 letter to, 2 related letters; 2 newspaper cl.
    - Blume, Bernhard, 1966 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 62)
    - Boenisch, Peter (Berliner Illustrierte), 1961 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 63)
    - The Boston Globe, 1961-1971 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 64)
      1 letter from, 27 letters to (15 were published as "Letters to the Editor"); clippings of published letters.
    - Clippings, primarily from The Boston Globe, Undated; 25 items (Box 4 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 65)
    - Boston Globe Book Festival (Martin Robbins), 1972 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 66)
      3 letters from, 1 letter to; 1 cl.
    - Brod, Max, 1963-1969 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 67)
      1 letter from, 1 letter to, 2 related letters; 1 cl.
    - Camus, Albert, 1958 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 68)
    - Commentary (Elliot E. Cohen, Editor), 1951 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 69)
    - Conacher, H. M., 1959 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 70)
    - Coronet (Fritz Bamberger), 1946-1947 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 71)
    - Counter / Measures (X. J. Kennedy), 1972-1973 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 72)
      3 letters from, 4 letters to; copies of Bates poems printed in Counter / Measures.
    - Cowie, Prof. Alexander, 1963 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 73)
      2 letters from, 2 letters to, 1 related letter.
    - Diestel, Hedwig, 1971-1972 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 74)
    - Doar, John (Asst. U.S. Attorney General), 1966 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 75)
      1 letter to; 1 cl.
    - Doubleday, Doran & Co. (Van H. Cartmell, LeBaron R. Barker, Jr), 1945-1947 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 76)
      5 letters from, 6 letters to.
    - Encore (Harrison Smith, Editor), 1946 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 77)
      5 letters from, 3 letters to.
    - Ernst, Morris L., 1967 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 78)
      1 letter to; 2 reprints.